











VAIBHAV DIXIT

+91 8800242220 | New Delhi | vaibhav.dixit1411@gmail.com

Cloud Solution Architect (Head of Engineering – Cloud Systems)

Versatile, trained, engaging, motivated and seasoned IT and Consulting Professional with 16+ years of experience in Solution Architecture, Cloud Computing, Private/Public/Hybrid/Multi- Cloud Design & Deployment, Infrastructure consulting, Cloud Migration, BCDR, DC Transformation/Migration, Application modernization, DC Consolidation, Remote Infrastructure Management.

Azure | Private Cloud Solutions | Hybrid Cloud | Azure Stack Hub | Azure Stack HCI | Azure Arc | Edge Computing | Automation | Migration | Solution Designing | Project Management | Strategic Planning | Escalations-Handling | L3/L4 Support | DR

Energetic, driven, and accomplished Cloud Expert with a track record of success in managing complex Cloud / IT modernization and system integration projects. Project management and engineering skills with genuine enthusiasm for resolving business challenges through technical innovation. Solutions driver who bridges the gap between business and technology while envisioning the bigger picture. Devises strategies to align multiple disciplines, coordinating efforts between business groups and driving complex systems integration for robust, high-quality systems that solve business problems and provide business results.

- IT Infrastructure & Standardization
 - **Business Transformation Solution**

- Public/Private Hybrid Cloud Strategy
- Disaster Recovery

Pre-Sales Support

Innovation

- Analytical Problem-Solving Abilities
- Performance Leadership Enhancement
- Team Collaboration, Coaching, & Motivation

Certifications / Exams / Trainings

Certified on -

Microsoft Cer	tified Trainer	Microsoft Az	ure Architect	Microsoft	Azure Architec	t AZ-303
(MCT)		Technologies		Design		
AZ-304	AZ-104	AZ-900	AWS-A	VCP	МСР	MCSE
MCTS	ITILv3					

Trained on -

PMP	AzureStack Hub	Agile	Kaizen	CCNA	CloudWatt
TOGAF 9	RHCA	Ansible	Microsoft Vital Signs	SCCM	Flexible Engine
AZ-600	AZ-500				

Professional Highlights

Led and implemented complex projects and Global teams—mitigated risks, managed requirements, and worked with project stakeholders while managing expectations at the department and project levels.

- Migration over CLOUD
- Cloud Image Factory
- Vulnerability Management

- Product Industrialization
- Techno Watch (Study)
- Vendor Technical Relations

Solution POC

- Problem Management support
- Solution Validation Committee

Professional Experiences

Orange Business Services: Gurugram, Haryana

Cloud Solution Architect (Head of Engineering – Cloud Systems)



(Aug 2012 - present)

Azure | Solutions Architect | Business Continuity Plan | Migration | SME | Innovation | Problem Management support | Support Queue Qualification | L3/L4 Support | Technology Roadmap creation | Vendor Management

As a Head of Engineering, working on a techno-management role with multiple responsibilities such as Solution Architects, Pre-Sales, SME. Involved in end to end planning, designing, building, and providing RUN support to Private / Public / Hybrid Cloud based environments.

Creating and managing Technology Roadmap followed by Release Management, POC & Product Industrialization of the products/solutions.

Solutions designs are planned with business continuity, High-Availability, Agile along with the Managed Services on top.

- Solution Block Owner for the solution management committee
- Vendor Technical management
- Working on hybrid cloud solution along with Azure Stack Hub/ Azure.
- Disaster Recovery solution using Zerto, DoubleTake (Carbonite), Azure Migrate
- People Manager, handling a team of highly technical experts
- SkillCenter Leader for Systems and Stack
- Subject Matter Expert (SME) for Cloud Solutions
- Support queue qualifications
- Vulnerability Management
- L3/L4 Incident / Problem Management support

HCL Technologies – NOIDA

Technical Lead

Client: - NCR Corporation, US



(Nov 2008 - Jul 2012)

ESXi | VMWare vCenter | Hyper-V | High Availability | HPE – DL/BL Servers | DELL Servers | Tape Library | Patch Management | DMZ | NetBackup | OS Troubleshooting | sysinternals | BSOD – Dump Analysis

Even though was only hired to be a "Wintel" expert, I went above and beyond the call of duty and surpassed everyone's expectations by gradually learning and performing roles such as VMware administrator, Database Administrator, OS (Operating System) Engineer, Application & Web Server Specialist, Server Hardware Engineer. I had the burning desire to provide value and make an invaluable impact on the entire product, which I successfully did. My invaluable contributions were not only recognized by our client *NCR Corporation*, but was also awarded with "Award of Achievement for All Round Performance" by HCL itself.

AccelFrontline Limited: New Delhi

Team Lead/Sr Engineer

Clients: - Aricent Technologies (Gurgaon) / Lufthansa Airlines (New Delhi)



(Jun 2005 - Oct 2008)

WSUS | Backup | PowerShell | WDS | Active Directory | Server-Client | Antivirus | Windows OS | RBAC | Patching

In the early days, there were no pre-defined automation tools to perform the system administration tasks easily. Customer/IT engineering were using the manual approach for *deployment of server, clients, agents, binaries, configurations, etc.* I started a centralized automated approach for OS deployment by using *Windows Deployment Services (WDS), automated the configuration deployment with batch and PowerShell scripts.* This approach also helped a lot while working on *WSUS, Backup, antivirus, application support, Role based access control (RBAC) implementation, Global account management activities.* I was able to increase the efficiency of the team with quicker response to the customer needs.

Education, Certification & Affiliation

- B. Tech (Information Technology) from RKGIT-Ghaziabad / UPTU in 2005 with 71% marks
- **Higher Secondary (PCM)** from CBSE / SDPS Public School in 2000 with 71% marks
- Senior Secondary from CBSE / SDPS Public School in 1998 with 61% marks

Achievements

- Received "Samaroh Gaurav Samman" award from "Parshuram Seva Sansthan" for coaching & mentoring the student of rural areas. (Social)
- Received Certificate on COVID-19 Awareness & Management from NATHEALTH & FICCI (Social)
- Volunteer for "Swachh Bharat Abhiyan 2019" (Social)
- Act and published Traffic Rules Awareness video on YouTube (Social)
- Played at U.P. State Badminton Competition held at KNIT Sultanpur (Sports)
- Won the college (RKGIT) badminton championship in 2003. (Sports)
- Won the School badminton championship in 2000 (Sports)
- Served as sports caption at school and college level (Sports)
- Received award for organizing the Teck Affair Quiz show in August 2020 (Orange)
- Received appreciation for successful transformation of SkillCenter models. (Orange)
- Received appreciations for managing and organizing the Solution Block Governance (Orange)
- Received loads of appreciations and awards for excellent L3 support and training for L2. (Orange)
- Achieved Silver membership of HCL and awarded as HCL Jewel (HCL)
- Received Best Performance Award many time from the customer (HCL)
- Cleared the International Engineers Exam organized by Fujitsu (AccelFrontline Limited) for Lufthansa Airlines customer
- Awarded by the Best Engineer's Award for JAS quarter 2006 (Accel Frontline Limited)